

- francis@kristi.se
- +46 704 02 88 04
- https://kristi.se
- Stockholm
- in Kristi Francis
- KristiF

English Native Swedish Native Assyrian Native Spanish B1

## Kristi Francis

Software engineer, M.sc. in C.Sci student

## About me

I'm a driven and energetic person with a passion for tech and learning. I've been programming since I was 9 years old and have worked with a lot of different personal projects throughout the years. I take pride in having a lot of interests and hobbies, including chess, cooking, baking, singing, and playing guitar. I'm also an avid traveller and I previously travelled solo for 6 months in South America, visiting 7 different countries, improving my social skills, and even learning conversational Spanish!

## Relevant experience

## **Software Engineer**

April 2023 - present

**Tidings** 

- Full responsibility over tech, including leading a team of 5 people.
- Planning and evaluating sprints.
- Building microservices using Azure Functions and Azure Container Instances.
- Developing and publishing a mobile app using React Native with Expo.
- Reviewing code and handling pull requests with Github.
- Building content-based news recommendations using text embeddings.
- Setting up CI/CD workflows for Azure functions using Github Actions.

#### Software engineering intern

Oct 2022 - April 2023

Chip

- · Contributing to the development of a web app using NextJS.
- · Webscraping using Selenium.
- Building a Reddit bot that generated 100k+ unique visitors.
- · Becoming more familiar with version control.

#### **Owner**

Jan 2021 - Sep 2022

Teknikfixaren i Stockholm

- Small company I started to get some experience running a company.
- Building websites using Wordpress and providing IT-support to individuals.

#### Store responsible

Jun 2018 - Jan 2021

Handshake Sweden AB

 Complete responsibility of the store including sales to individuals and companies, teaching new employees, and shelving and organizing products.

## **Education**

# Degree programme in Media Technology and Computer Science

Aug 2020 - present

KTH Royal Institute of Technology

Bachelor's thesis: *Object shape and depth perception in VR* (accepted to CHI 2024 as "Late-breaking work"). During my time at KTH, I've taken on opportunities to improve in various areas, including:

- · Building a real-time sign language letter recognition model with machine learning.
- Serving as a course assistant in an introductory Python course, where I graded assignments and helped students.
- Managing inventory for Medias Klubbmästeri (MKM), purchasing new items, and assisting in organizing student events.

## Natural Science programme

Aug 2013 - Jun 2016

Viktor Rydbergs Gymnasium Odenplan

## **Skills**

## Python

Lots of experience working with Python for different projects. Some examples include:

- · Fullstack application with Django.
- · Backend application with Flask.
- Machine learning and data science utilizing Sklearn, Pandas, Numpy, and Tensorflow.

#### Javascript

I've worked a lot with Javascript and different Javascript frameworks for my current position. My experience includes:

- Backend application with NodeJS.
- Frontend application with React (specifically NextJS).
- Mobile app with React Native.
- · Chrome extension using vanilla Javscript.

#### Leadership

I've had the pleasure of leading a team of 5 people in my current position at Tidings. With little experience, I've learned the following:

- Project management utilizing agile methodology, including planning sprints and evaluating during and after to improve our workflow.
- Mentoring interns, helping them when they get stuck and teaching them new skills to improve their contributions.
- Strategizing different solutions and approaches with regards to execution time and usage of resources.
- Taking responsibility and being accountable for problems that arise.